# Jesper Kjeldgaard



theispr@gmail.com

I'm passionate about improving peoples lives by solving real problems with software products.

For the past 3 years I have worked as a developer in two startups, both revolving around Ruby on Rails applications. Throughout this time I have evolved my skills in building features that focus on solving the problem in the simplest and fastest way possible. I believe that getting a feature out in front of the user and iterating on it based on their feedback and behaviour, is the most important aspect of whether it will be a success.

I love being involved in the creative process from idea conception to deploying and maintaining the finished product, and this is one of the reasons I have decided to become self-employed as a freelancer in 2015. I am well-versed in both front-end and back-end development, not shying away from anything that needs doing to get the job done.

If you have any ideas or projects that you think could benefit from my skills and knowledge, or just want to have a chat, please don't hesitate to get in touch.

## **Experience**

#### Webyard (Owner), Software Consultant. January 2015 - now

Working with Ruby, Rails and Web technologies for several clients. My clients currently include <u>Bitsilk</u> and <u>Studiz</u>.

#### HouseTrip, Software Engineer. April 2013 - December 2014

Working on <a href="https://example.com">housetrip.com</a>, a large Rails application with many moving parts. I was involved in several big projects like; a responsive redesign of several key pages, introducing feature flags, migrating our CI to TravisCI and lots of initiatives to improve conversion rates.

At HouseTrip I was also a Lead Software Engineer in a team of 5 from 10/2014 to 09/2015. During this time I managed 2-3 engineers, helped the PM plan and estimate projects and in general focused on keeping the team on track and thriving.

## **Evently, Software Engineer. November 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 5 months)**

At Evently I have worked on making online event marketing easier. This includes adding features to and maintaining a large SaaS Rails application, and building new API consuming/providing applications. The technologies I used whilst at Evently include: Redis, MongoDB, RSpec, SOA, EC2/Heroku, Postgresql and EmberJS.

One project I've worked on whilst at Evently was a service to distribute events to numerous listing sites using Capybara. Another project was creating public event pages for events. The public event pages are managed from a separate application which updates the pages through an API. Most projects were developed using Kanban.

#### Harmonypark, Intern. March 2011 - September 2011 (7 months)

At Harmonypark I worked on a large time management Rails application and learned a lot about BDD and working with large applications.

#### Capana, Student Developer. May 2009 - September 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Developing web applications internally and for customers using PHP and MySQL. I worked on a 2-person team and delivered a work-planning application to a large telephone company.

#### **Education**

#### MSc Internet Application Development. October 2010 - November 2011

Middlesex University, London, United Kingdom

Grade: 2:1 (Pass with Merit)

Notable projects: Ruby web server. Web-based file storage service.

#### BSc. Software Engineering. September 2007 - June 2010

Aalborg University, Aalborg, Denmark

Grade: B average. A in my final project.

Notable projects: An Implicitly parallel programming language (Java). A social network for

universities (C#/ASP.NET).

# **Technical Skills Summary**

- Languages: Ruby, JavaScript (+CoffeeScript).
- Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra and Backbone.js.
- Databases: Postgresql, MongoDB, Redis and Mysql.
- Platforms: AWS and Heroku.
- Testing: RSpec, Jasmine and Cucumber.
- Methodologies: XP, Kanban and Scrum.
- Msc: HTML, CSS and Sass.

To satisfy my curiosity about software development I'm currently learning functional programming in Clojure and how to build native Android applications. If you need a developer for either technology, I'd be happy to help out at a reduced rate.

## More information

thejspr.com github.com/thejspr linkedin.com/in/jesperkjeldgaard